Guide to the American Documents Collection, 1700-1851
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
American Documents Collection,
1700-1851.
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library.
2.6 linear ft. (850 items in 7 boxes)
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078556
History
Scope and Content
The collection is principally of New Hampshire documents, dated 1745-1760 and numbering 240 items, of which all but one are deeds. The remainder of the material consists of twelve South Carolina items for dates from 1709 to 1836, being grants, deeds, bonds, and other legal and business papers; and two North Carolina documents - a will of 1779 and a land grant of 1787.
Also documents from the Towns of Waldoboro and Exeter in Maine consisting of town and school records, 1813-1850, and a property record book of Moses Hodson, Bowdoin, Maine, 1800-1820; nineteen documents, 1798-1800, chiefly dated from Pownalborough, Lincoln County, Mass., including orders to attach property of various citizens for non-payment of debt; sixteen documents, 1800-1829, chiefly dated from New York City and including trial documents, partnership agreements, and indentures for sale of property; and three documents, 1801-1807, from Connecticut, including summons and receipts.
Subjects
Hodson, Moses.; Waldboro (Me.: Town)--Politics and government.; Exeter (Me.: Town)--Politics and government.; New York (N.Y.)--Commerce.; Real property--New Hampshire.; Real property--North Carolina.; Real property--South Carolina.; Real property--Maine--Bowdoin.; Real property--Massachusetts--Pownalborough.; Land grants--North Carolina.; Land grants--South Carolina.; Debt--Massachusetts--Pownalborough.
Access Restrictions
This collection is located off-site. You will need to request this material at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1950 M50 Westerfield, Mrs. Jason Purchase
Finding aid in repository.
- American Documents Collection
  - Connecticut Documents
    - 3 documents, summons and receipts, 1801-1807 (Box 2)
  - Maine Documents
    - Town and School Records of Waldoboro & Exeter 1813-1850 (Box 1)
    - Moses Hodson Property Record Book, Bowdoin, 1800-1820 etc. (Box 1)
    - Oversized Documents (Box 8)
  - Massachusetts Documents
    - 19 documents, chiefly dated from Pownalborough, Lincoln County, 1798-1800 (Box 3)
    - Orders to attach property of various citizens for non-payment of debt. (Box 3)
  - New Hampshire Documents
    - 240 Items, of which all but one are deeds, 1745-1760 (Box 4-5)
  - New York Documents
    - 16 documents, chiefly dated from New York City. Included are trial documents, partnership agreements, indentures for sale of property, etc., 1800-1829 (Box 6)
  - North Carolina Documents
    - Will, 1779 (Box 7)
    - Land Grant, 1787 (Box 7)
  - South Carolina Documents
    - 12 items, being grants, deeds, bonds and other legal and business papers, 1709-1836 (Box 7)